[Music]
former US Central Intelligence Agency
officer John kiraku has been sentenced
to 30 months in prison for blowing the
cover of another CIA agent marking the
first time in 27 years that anyone has
been sentenced to prison for disclosing
a covert agent's
identity kaku's case stems back to 2008
when he revealed the agent's name in an
email to a reporter he had repeatedly
helped journalists with information on
the cia's inter ation technique of water
boarding and its interrogation of
al-Qaeda operative Abu
Zaba I would like to thank the dozens of
former and active duty CIA officers and
FBI agents and assistant us attorneys
who rallied to my side although most of
them had to do so privately I thank them
for their their cards their emails their
donations to my defense fund it was
their friendship and the support of my
friends and family that uh really got me
through this prosecutors told reporters
outside the courthouse that the leaks of
the sort kiraku was charged with go to
the heart of the nation's intelligence
Service as the judge just said uh in
court today's sentence should be a
reminder to uh every individual who
works for the government who comes into
the possession of closely held sensitive
uh information regarding the national uh
defense or the identity of a covert
agent uh that it is critical that that
information uh remain secure and not
spill out uh into the public domain or
be shared with others who don't have uh
authorized access to it after pleading
guilty kyaku sentence closes one of six
prosecutions the Obama Administration
has pursued against alleged leakers of
classified
information